原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 杨一勾  Lynn_宁  木浅   小食人魔
翻译：Giggles  辰星晓Reginamoon   校对：木浅  某羽
时间轴：念念 烟幕迟迟 Toozii
后期：斯人      总监：木浅
诉 讼 双 雄
第七季   第五集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
我们交往并不违规
There's no violation with us seeing each other.
我不是想要逃避什么惩罚
This isn't something that I am trying to get away with.
而是关于我内心的感受
It's something I'm feeling inside.
而且他再等1个月就假释了
My son was up for parole next month.
他根本就不会和别人打架
He wouldn't have gotten into a fight.
至少有二十名囚犯投诉
There's got to be at least 20 complaints
未能在预定日期顺利出狱
of prisoners being denied their release date.
而且他们每个人都受伤了
And every one of them involves injuries
还被指有一些含混不清的违纪行为
and some kind of vague disciplinary action.
如果我们的律所和本案扯上任何关系
If our firm is in any way associated with that case,
-都会丢一个大客户  -我放弃
- we lose a huge client. - I'm not working on it.
那就出一份书面声明
Then you're gonna put that in writing.
保证你与本案无关
You have nothing to do with this case.
我的工作要求要有个慎重的好名声
My job requires a reputation for discretion.
他不会告诉任何人的
He'll never tell a soul,
你的生意也不会受到影响
and your business will stay intact.
你做冒牌律师这么多年
You lived a lie for years.
你连做一个小案子的秘密都藏不住吗
You can't keep a secret about working one goddamn case?
我们有份工作给你
We have a job we'd like to offer you.
我不跟信不过的人合作
I don't do business with people I don't trust.
你可以帮助他们
You can help these people.
我要五万美元
I want $50,000.
奥利弗  是我  我加入
Oliver, it's me. I'm in.
你给哈维的承诺怎么办
What about your promise to Harvey?
哈维的事我来解决
You let me worry about Harvey.
等等  你要走了
Wait, you're leaving?
怎么不叫醒我
Why didn't you wake me?
因为还有一小时你的闹钟才会响
'Cause you still have an hour before your alarm goes off.
才6:30  你要去哪
6:30. Where are you going?
哈维不可能有事让你这么早去办
There's no way you have something this early for Harvey.
我跟奥利佛有诊所的事
I got something at the clinic with Oliver.
他需要我帮他办一件案子
He needs my help with a case.
等等
Wait.
我今晚想跟你一起吃饭的
I was hoping we could have dinner tonight.
我今晚大概也得去见奥利佛
I probably have to meet with Oliver tonight, too.
那你不如让哈维给你放假
Well, then why don't you ask Harvey for some time off
去处理好你们的工作
to take care of what you're working on?
他已经允许我这么两头跑了
He's already letting me go back and forth.
我不想占便宜
I don't wanna take advantage.
迈克  我就是担心你
Mike, I'm just worried about you
忙过头
burning the candle at both ends.
我们昨晚说过了
We talked about it last night.
不会永远如此的  我保证
It's not gonna last forever. I promise.
好吧
Okay.
继续睡吧
Go back to bed.
奥利佛  我不能在这儿一整天
Oliver, I can't be here all day.
我们赶紧的吧  你安排了什么
So let's get down to it. What do you got?
去布鲁克林  见马克・史蒂文斯
I've got us a meeting in Brooklyn with Marc Stevens.
那是谁
Who's Marc Stevens?
他是我们集体诉讼的18号原告
He is plaintiff number 18 in our class.
-我们约好了九点  -很好
- We're meeting him at nine. - Great.
那么我们就有时间想个说法了
That'll give us time to come up with our cover story.
迈克  我知道严格讲你不能做这个
Mike, I know you're not technically allowed to work on this,
但这里没人会出卖你的
but no one here is gonna rat you out.
没这么简单  奥利佛  我们说过了
It's not a technicality. Oliver, we've been over this.
我参与这案子可能造成它
Me working on this case means the whole thing
完全被推翻
could get tossed out.
我懂
I get it.
只有两个人知情  我和你
There's only two people in the loop, me and you.
没错  所以如果纳森问起
Exactly. So if Nathan asks...
纳森问起什么
Nathan asks what?
纳森
Nathan.
我就是在跟奥利佛说
I was just telling Oliver
如果你看我看烦了
that if you get sick of seeing me around here,
那也没办法
then he's gonna have to tell you too bad,
我是不会允许布鲁克林经济房
'cause I am not gonna let the Brooklyn Housing Project
继续欺压住户的
keep bullying its tenants.
你自己解决不了那个吗
You can't handle the BHP on your own?
我也行  但有迈克支援更好
I can, but it's nice having Mike give me some backup.
好
Good.
老实说  你让我签了奥利佛的
Tell you the truth, after you made me sign
监狱案的利益冲突放弃书后
that conflict of interest waiver on Oliver's prison case,
我以为你不会再怎么出现了呢
I didn't think you'd be around here that much at all.
还剩什么给我了吗
Is there anything left for me?
没  你起晚了  所以错过了我给你做早餐
No, you slept in late so you missed me making you breakfast.
好啊  但我要说
I see, but for the record,
热速食食物不叫给我做早餐
heating up Pop-Tarts isn't making me breakfast.
那我补偿你一下
Well, how 'bout I make it up to you
不带你去吃午饭吧
and not take you out to lunch?
多谢你的不邀请
I appreciate the non-invitation,
但今天不行
but I can't today.
-得了  为什么  -我有预约
- Come on, why not? - I have an appointment.
你什么时候还中午见客户了
Since when do you see patients at lunch?
不是病人  哈维
It isn't with a patient, Harvey.
是我的律师
It's actually with my lawyer.
什么意思  你的律师
What do you mean, your lawyer?
没事的  就是一个
It's nothing. It's a nuisance suit
前生意伙伴侵害诉讼
from an ex-business partner.
是谁在替你处理
Well, who's handling it for you?
希望你不是要建议
I hope you're not about to suggest
你来替我处理
that you handle it for me.
不是  但我可以替你找第二好的人
I'm not, but I can get you to the next best person.
这人有名字吗
And does this person have a name?
路易・利特
Louis Litt.
就是你揍过的那个
The one you punched in the face?
宝拉  他是最合适的人选
Paula, he's the best man for the job.
听我的  路易是只斗牛犬
I'm telling you, Louis is a pit bull.
谁说我想要斗牛犬了
And who says I want a pit bull?
听着  不管是什么事
Listen to me, if whatever this thing is,
如果已经提起了诉讼
it's reached the level of a lawsuit,
你就会需要路易那样的律师
you're gonna need a lawyer like Louis
不管你想不想
whether you like it or not.
多谢你的担心  哈维
Well, I appreciate your concern, Harvey,
但我更想自己解决
but I prefer to handle this myself.
但如果你还想帮忙
But if you still want to help,
再给我买盒新果馅饼吧
why don't you buy me a new box of Pop-Tarts?
什么味儿都行  只要是草莓味儿的
Any flavor will do, as long as it's strawberry.
太扯了
It was total bullshit.
你是说你没打架吗
Are you saying you didn't get in a fight at all?
没  我是打架了
No, I got in a fight,
但那是为了活命
but it was only to stay alive.
跟我们说说  我们是你这边的
Just tell us what happened. We're on your side.
我本来还有俩月就出来了
Look, I was two months from getting out, okay?
我本打算出狱之前
I was gonna keep my head down
每天都低调做人
every single day until I walked.
一转眼  一个大块头混蛋
Next thing I know, some big-ass son of a bitch
压在了我身上  我却被延长了刑期
is on top of me, and I'm the one that gets extra time?
-他叫什么  -我不知道
- What was his name? - I don't know, man.
我根本不知道
I have no idea.
马克  我不知道你是不是担心报复
Look, Marc, I don't know if you're afraid of payback or something,
但我们需要知道一切
but we need to know everything if we're gonna--
我不是担心报复
I'm not afraid of no payback, okay?
我真不知道那人是谁
I don't know who he was.
我要是知道  就告诉你了
And if I knew, I would tell you.
那地方夺走了我两年的时间
Look, that place took two years of my life.
之后又加刑两年  就因为偷了几个电视
Two extra years on top of the two for stealing a few TVs.
如果你们要告他们  我想加入
If you're going after them, then I want in on this.
你可以加入  但我在监狱
Then you're in, but I was in prison
待过一段  比你时间短
an even shorter time than you,
我还知道我囚区所有人的名字
and I still knew all the guys' names on my cellblock.
所以要么他是新来的  要么是你转去了他那里
So either he was new to yours or you were new to his.
不管怎样  我需要知道事情经过
Either way, I need to know what happened.
简单  我那晚去了另一个囚区吃饭
That's easy. I had dinner in a different block that night.
-为什么  -他们叫我去的
- Why did you do that? - 'Cause they told me to.
-谁  -守卫
- Who told you to? - The guards.
他们会一时兴起就公布在墙上
Look, they would post it on the wall whenever they felt like it
以免我们太安逸了
to keep us from getting too comfortable.
就是说  你不知道是哪个守卫
Which means you don't know the guard
决定让你过去
who decided to move you,
也不知道跟你打架的人是谁
and you don't know the name of the guy you got in a fight with.
听我的  我没撒谎
I'm telling you guys, man, I'm not lying.
我相信
I don't think you are.
我觉得那是他们的安排
I think they set it up that way.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
诉讼双雄 第七季 第五集
-路易  -等等
- Louis. - Hold on, man.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
玩桌面沙包
Playing desktop cornhole.
能安抚我的情绪
It's supposed to calm my nerves.
好吧  很不想打断你  但我需要你帮忙
Okay, I hate to interrupt, but I need to ask a favor.
随便开口  你需要什么
Anything. What do you need?
你知道我去年一直在见心理医生吧
You know I was seeing a psychiatrist last year, right?
哈维  假如这事有关你的健康
Harvey, if this has to do with your well-being,
我洗耳恭听  但你也知道
I'm all ears, but as you know,
我不是提供心理健康服务的持证从业者
I'm not a licensed practitioner of mental health services--
路易  不是你想的那样
Louis, that's not it.
听着  我的心理医生被告了
Look, my psychiatrist is being sued.
她自己有律师  但我不信任他
She has her own attorney, but I don't trust him,
我想让你接这个案子
and I want you to handle it.
我没明白
I don't understand.
假如你不信任他  你自己为什么不接
If you don't trust him, why aren't you taking it?
我告诉过你了  她是我的心理医生
I told you, she's my therapist.
没错  曾经是
Yeah, was.
这不代表你不能帮她处理法律问题
That doesn't stop you from helping her with a legal issue.
好吧  你想听真相是吧
All right, you want the truth?
我在和她约会
I'm seeing her.
你在和自己的心理医生约会
You're dating your therapist?
听着  我不需要你对我说教  路易
Look, I don't need a lecture from you, Louis.
这可不是说教  哈维
This isn't a lecture, Harvey.
如果你在和自己的心理医生约会
If you're dating your therapist
又被别人发现  可能会害她丢掉执照
and someone finds out about it, she could lose her license.
不  不会的
No, she can't.
我们是在
We didn't start dating until
官方禁止期之后才开始约会的
after the official waiting period was over.
我需要你向我保证
I want your word on that,
因为假如有人问起...
because if someone ever asks--
我向你保证  我不会在这事上撒谎
You have my word. I wouldn't lie about that.
好的  我会去和她谈谈的
Okay, I'll go talk to her.
等等  哈维
But wait a second, Harvey,
唐娜知道你俩的事吗
does Donna have any idea about the two of you?
不  她不知道
No, she doesn't,
目前我想保持这种状态
and for right now I'd like to keep it that way.
偷几台电视蹲了六年  这有问题
Six years for stealing a few TVs, that's not right.
-的确  -我们下一步该怎么做
- No, it's not. - What's our next move?
我们得查明
We gotta figure out
是谁让一个还有两个月就能假释的人
who decided a guy two months from parole
到另一个囚区吃饭的
should eat in a different cellblock.
我们要怎样才能查明啊
How the hell are we gonna do that?
我不知道  奥利佛
I don't know, Oliver,
但如今你得自己一个人去查明了
but right now you're gonna have to work on that yourself.
什么意思  你要去哪里
What are you talking about? Where are you going?
假如我不去上班
If I don't show my face at work,
哈维一定会起疑的
Harvey is gonna get suspicious.
迈克  你确定我们这么做值得吗
Mike, are you sure what we're doing is worth it?
奥利佛  一开始明明
Oliver, you're the one that pushed me
是你推着我管这个案子的
to stick with this in the first place.
你也听见了  他们加倍了他的刑期
You heard that guy, they doubled his sentence.
克里斯・雷耶斯死了
Chris Reyes is dead.
所以是的  值得
Yeah, it's worth it.
你一定是哈维・斯佩克特
You must be Harvey Specter.
谢谢你见我  瑞克
Thanks for meeting me, Rick.
我知道作为称霸能源产业的人你时间宝贵
I know dominating the energy sector is a full-time job.
有话直说  斯佩克特先生
Get to the point, Mr. Specter.
我抽时间见你不是为了听你拍我马屁的
I didn't interrupt my day just so you could kiss my ass.
那让我告诉你你必须见我的原因
Then let me tell you why you did.
洛克伍德能源公司准备发行一种太阳能板
Lockwood Energy is about to release a solar panel
看上去非常像
that looks a hell of a lot like the one
你们开发了好几年的那款
you've been developing for years.
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
因为我并没有把一整个早上
Because I didn't spend all morning
花在提高我的拍马屁技巧上
brushing up on my ass-kissing techniques.
那你也一定知道洛克伍德的绿色能源部
Then you also know that Lockwood's Green Division
从创立到现在只有三个月
has only existed for three months.
他们偷了那项技术
They stole that technology.
所以你应该签约让我代理
Which is why you should sign with me
这样我就能把它夺回来
so I can go get it back.
我已经签了一家律所了
I already have a law firm.
我为何不让他们来处理这件事
Why shouldn't I let them handle this?
因为你不会想要一个
Because you don't want the guy
在洛克伍德偷走了
who's gonna sue Lockwood
你女朋友之后才去告他们的律所
after they've stolen your girlfriend.
你想要的是一个能在洛克伍德行动之前
You want the guy who's gonna put them in the ground
就把他们干掉的律所
before they get the chance.
你倒是挺自信的
You're pretty sure of yourself.
你想要一个不自信的人来处理这事吗
You want someone handling this who isn't?
听着  你何不花一周的时间考虑一下
Look, why don't you take the week to think it over.
当然了  在你纠结的同时
Of course, while you're doing that,
洛克伍德会迅速把你的产品投入市场
Lockwood's gonna be rushing your product to market,
等到那时  你的董事会就会想
and when they do, your board's gonna be wondering
在你有机会的时候你为什么没有雇用我
why you didn't hire me when you had the chance.
好吧  斯佩克特先生  你赢了
All right, Mr. Specter, you win.
你有三天时间
You've got three days.
看看你是不是真有你自己认为的那么好
Let's see if you're as good as you think you are.
你一定就是宝拉・阿加德
You must be Paula Agard.
抱歉  但我们认识吗
I'm sorry, but do we know each other?
暂时还不  但很高兴认识你
Not yet, but it is a pleasure to meet you.
我是路易・利特
I'm Louis Litt, and I understand
听说你在找律师
you are looking for a lawyer.
我有律师  他叫皮特・夏恩珀特
I have a lawyer, and his name's Peter Shumpert.
皮特今天不会来了
Ah, Peter will not be joining you today.
什么
Excuse me?
我确信他是个好人
I mean, I'm sure he's a nice guy,
但他不是头牌诉讼律师
but he's not a litigator.
我没看出那一点和这件事有什么关系
Well, I don't see what that has to do with this.
当一名律师让他的客户见了另一名律师
When an attorney lets a client meet with another attorney,
相信我  这说明你需要更好的诉讼代理人
trust me, you need better representation.
我知道你是一名多么优秀的律师  利特先生
I already know what an excellent attorney you are, mr. Litt.
哈维向我推荐你时已经就已经赞美过你了
Harvey said as much when he offered your services.
-那你为什么拒绝他  -因为...
- And why'd you turn him down? - Because...
这件事上有一些东西
there are things about this situation
是我不想和哈维分享的
that I'd rather not share with Harvey.
我完全能够理解
I can understand that completely,
无论是什么事  假如我是你的律师
and whatever they are, if I were your attorney,
我是绝对不会向他透露这些事的
there is no way in hell that he would hear them from me.
我向你保证
That I can assure you.
好吧  好吧  路易
Okay. Okay, Louis.
你可以做我的代理人
You can represent me.
很好  那你先给我讲讲你们之间的过往吧
Good. So let's start by you giving me the history.
这就是重点
Well, that's just it.
我们从前不仅仅只是生意伙伴
We weren't solely business partners.
我们住在一起  我们一起工作
We were living together, we had a practice together.
然后发生什么了
What happened?
他提出分手  伤透了我的心
He broke it off, and he broke my heart.
我把生意中他想要的一切都给了他
I gave him everything in the partnership that he wanted
就是为了离开那一切  离开他
just to be rid of it and of him.
然后呢
And then?
几个我们之前的小组病人对他的治疗反应不佳
Some of our group patients didn't respond well to his treatment,
所以他们开始单独来见我
so they started coming to see me privately.
单独来还是偷偷来
Privately or secretly?
假如你是想问
If what you're asking
我知不知道这样违反了我们之间的协议
is if I knew it was a violation of our agreement,
那么是的  我知道
then yes, I did.
但这些人当时很痛苦
But these people were hurting.
然后凭良心你不能拒绝他们
And you couldn't in good conscience turn them away.
的确  我不能
No, I couldn't.
宝拉  我向你保证
Paula, you have my word,
这事你知我知
this stays between you and me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
奥利佛  告诉我你有发现
Oliver, tell me you found something.
什么都没有
Nothing.
他们有个随机分配狱警的系统
They've got a system that randomly assigns changes from time to time.
那你打来电话干什么
Well, what are you calling me for?
因为我们的案子可能和狱警没关系
Because there might not be a link between our cases and the guards,
但我在斗殴中却有所发现
but I did find one between the fights.
-继续说  -就目前我们手头的20件案子
- I'm listening. - Out of the 20 cases we have so far,
总共只有四名囚犯参与了斗殴
the fights have been with a total of only four inmates,
我找到了完美的证人  杰马克斯・科林斯
and I got the perfect one, JaMarcus Collins.
他刑期十年  就在C区服刑
He's in the middle of a ten-year sentence
和克里斯・雷耶斯和马克・史蒂文斯
on cellblock C, one over from Chris Reyes
分区相邻
and Marc Stevens.
那我们得去拜访一下科林斯先生了
Well, then we gotta pay Mr. Collins a visit.
我已经安排好了  一个小时后去接你
I've already set it up. I'll pick you up in an hour.
好
Great.
那我们在布鲁克林房屋委员会见面  好
I will see you at the Brooklyn Housing Authority then. Okay.
无论你在做什么  都停下来
Whatever you're doing, put it on hold.
我有个需要唱红白脸的状况  要你帮忙
I've got a good cop/bad cop situation and I need you.
等等  现在吗
Wait, right now?
不  星期四开始数三个月后
No, three months from Thursday.
-好了  走吧  -哈维  我去不了
- Come on, let's go. - Harvey, I can't.
什么叫去不了
What do you mean you can't?
我和奥利佛
I ha--I have a meeting
约好要在布鲁克林房屋委员见面
with Oliver at the Brooklyn Housing Authority.
-我不能把他晾一边  -奥利佛
- I can't leave him hanging. - Oliver?
你刚做了一个无偿案  这有违约定
You just did a pro bono. That's not our deal.
我知道哈维  但我几星期前就在准备了
I know that, Harvey, but I put this in motion weeks ago.
我不知道你会派给我另一件无偿案
I didn't know you were gonna give me another pro bono.
好吧  我自己解决
Fine, I'll handle it myself.
无论你和奥利佛在做什么
Look, whatever you're doing with Oliver,
快点结束
wrap it the hell up.
我招你回来不是让你在我需要时抛弃我的
I didn't bring you back to not be here when I need you.
利普希茨医生  我是路易
Dr. Lipschitz, it's Louis.
我不知道还能怎么说
Look, there's no two ways to say this.
那天晚上我出格了
I was way out of line the other night,
我知道你关心我
and I know you care about me,
并不仅仅是因为你有责任
and not just because you have an obligation to.
所以如果不是太麻烦的话
So if it's not too much trouble,
我想继续我们的治疗
I would like to resume our sessions, please.
请回电  谢谢
Please call me back. Thanks.
路易  我得和你谈谈哈维的事
Louis, I need to talk to you about Harvey.
他怎么了
What about him?
我只是想确定
I just want to make sure that you and he
你们俩之间很好
are on good terms.
是的  唐娜  我们很好
Yeah, Donna, we're on good terms.
你确定吗  因为我们要齐心协力
Are you sure? 'Cause we all pulled together
重新站稳脚跟
to get back on solid footing,
早些时候我看到你们两个缩在这里
and I saw the two of you huddled up in here earlier,
我不想事情朝着
and I'd hate to think that things are going
错误的方向发展
in the wrong direction.
没有  不是朝着错误的方向的发展  唐娜
No, not going in the wrong direction, Donna.
不必担心
There is no need to worry.
我的确很担心  路易
Well, I do worry, Louis.
因为我知道你现在的心理状态
Because I know what kind of mental state you're still in,
我知道一点点小事也能触及到你
and I know that the slightest thing can touch you off,
-我知道  -唐娜
- and I know that-- - Look, Donna,
跟你说  我们之间很好
for your information, we are on such good terms
哈维...
that Harvey--
哈维怎么了
That Harvey what?
没什么
Nothing.
路易  怎么了
Louis, what's going on?
好了  唐娜
Okay, look, Donna,
我只和你说一次
I'm only gonna tell you this once.
哈维让我帮他处理一件事
Harvey asked me to handle a matter for him.
是私事  他相信我
It's personal. He trusts me with it.
现在  如果你信我的话  你就信我说的
Now, if you trust me at all, you'll take my word for the fact
我们之间很好
that Harvey and I are on good terms.
好
Okay.
我相信你
I trust you.
哈维・斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
上次见面我们没有正式介绍
We didn't have a proper introduction the last time we met.
霍莉・科伦维尔
Holly Cromwell.
有何贵干  科伦维尔小姐
What do you want, Ms. Cromwell?
真是没礼貌
So much for formalities.
我很忙
I got a lot on my plate.
没时间讲礼貌
I don't have time for formalities.
如果你带上我  也许就有了
If you brought me on, maybe you would.
你说什么
Excuse me?
猎头公司待遇不够好斯佩克特先生
Headhunting isn't cutting it for me, Mr. Specter.
我想重新入局
I want back in the game,
既然你是我出局的理由
and since you're the reason I'm out of the game,
你应该雇我当你的全职内部顾问
you should hire me as a full-time in-house consultant.
所以你想让我出于内疚救济你吗
So you want me to give you a handout out of guilt?
我不想要救济
I don't want a handout.
但是你承诺不会毁掉我的名声的
But you made me a promise you wouldn't ruin my reputation.
你想让我说什么
What do you want me to say?
你做的事情很危险
What you do is dangerous.
我想让你说你许下了你做不到的诺言
I want you to say you make promises you can't keep.
顺便一提  如果你不觉得我有价值
And by the way, you wouldn't have sent that Rachel woman back to me
就不会派那个叫瑞秋的女孩再来找我
if you didn't know what I do is worth it.
首先  我从来没有派过任何人再去找你
Okay, first of all, I never sent anyone back to you.
第二  无论你认为你适合什么样的工作
And second, whatever job you think you're suited for
我的律所都没有这样的职位
doesn't exist in my firm.
贝克・辛姆斯和沃克・斯坦就有
It does at Baker Simms and Walker Stein.
我不会专门为一个唯一的技能
Yeah, well, I'm not looking to make a spot on the payroll
就是越界的人设新岗  开工资的
for someone whose only skill set is crossing lines.
你是说因为你完全可以自己越界
You mean when you cross them so well yourself.
我说了  科伦维尔小姐  我很忙
Like I said, Ms. Cromwell, I got a lot on my plate.
给我一杯麦卡伦  不加冰
Give me a Macallan, neat.
洛克伍德能源公司的股票猛涨
The way Lockwood stock shot up,
为什么不双倍持有呢
why not make it a double?
抱歉  我不认识你
I'm sorry, I don't recognize you.
你是在商业事务上班吗
Do you work in Business Affairs?
不  我的工作是因为你想将加尔万达因的
No, I work in suing your ass for trying to pass off
太阳能电池板占为己有告倒你
Galvadyne's solar panels as your own.
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are,
我也不知道你在说什么
and I don't know what you're talking about.
但那项技术是我们自己研发的
We developed that technology in-house.
扯淡
Oh, bullshit.
那项技术历时多年才能开发出来
That technology takes years to develop,
而你的整个部门也就从上周二
and your entire division's only been in existence
才开始存在的
since last Tuesday.
我能说什么呢
What can I say?
当你投资给正确的人才
When you invest in the right talent,
你就是能创造奇迹  据我所知
you can move mountains, and last I checked,
比竞争对手聪明可不犯法
being smarter than your competition wasn't illegal.
如果你有你说的一半聪明
Well, if you're half as smart as you say you are,
现在就会把我们的产品还回来
you'd give us our product back now,
或者我们之后为此夺走你的公司
or we'll take your company from you later.
如果你不是和联调局一起来的话
If you're here without the FBI,
就意味着你是个虚张声势的勒索专家
it means you're just a shakedown artist
你没有一丁点的证据证明你的主张
without a shred of evidence to back up your claims.
不  这意味着我是在给你个改正的机会
No, it means I'm giving you the chance to make it right.
因为我一旦证明了你偷了我们的技术
Because once I prove you stole our technology,
你庆祝的唯一一件事
the only thing you'll be celebrating
就是欺诈重罪的定罪了
is a felony fraud conviction.
谢谢你和我们见面  科林斯先生
Thanks for meeting us, Mr. Collins.
我是奥利佛・格雷迪  这位是我同事
I'm Oliver Grady, and this is my associate.
你的律师同事有名字吗
Your associate got a name?
我的名字没有我要问的问题重要
My name's not as important as the questions I have.
比如为什么去年11月4日
Like why did you incite a brawl in the cafeteria
你在午餐时间在餐厅煽动斗殴
during lunch on November 4th of last year?
搞什么
What is this?
你们来不是为了谈恢复我假释机会的事吗
I thought you were here to talk about reviving my shot at parole.
我们当然也可以谈那个
We can absolutely talk about that,
在你告诉我们为什么和监狱合谋
after you tell us why you conspired with this prison
延长你狱友的刑期之后
to get your fellow inmates' sentences extended.
扯淡  警卫
This is bullshit. Guard!
听着  你可以不告诉我们
Listen, you don't have to talk to us.
但这件事要曝光
But this thing comes out,
别说五年内出狱
instead of getting out in five years,
你这辈子都得在监狱里呆着了
you're gonna spend the rest of your life in here.
好吧  你们想知道什么
All right, what do you wanna know?
先谈谈是谁让你跟那些快要出狱的人
Let's start with who's telling you to pick fights
挑事掐架的吧
with guys who are about to get out.
没人让我跟别人挑事掐架
Nobody ever told me to pick a fight with anybody.
我只知道  我这片牢房来了新人
All I know is new guy comes into the block,
我就该教训教训他
I'm supposed to teach him a lesson.
没人告诉你的话  你怎么会知道
Well, how do you know that if nobody ever told you?
大概是两年前的事
It happened, like, two years ago.
我和人打起来了  他们把我拖走
I got in a fight with a guy, they dragged me away.
我以为自己要被关禁闭了
Thought they were gonna throw me in Solitary.
结果他们把另一个人关了禁闭
Instead, they threw him in Solitary.
我回到囚室  发现有台全新游戏机
I get back to my cell, brand-new PlayStation in there.
我猜你从没想过要问为什么
And let me guess, you never thought to ask why.
我知道原因  也不想失去我的游戏机
I knew why, and I'm not giving up my goddamn PlayStation.
你愿意出庭作证吗
You willing to testify to that in court?
你们能让我提前出狱吗
You really gonna get me out of here early?
我猜也是
Yeah, I didn't think so.
警卫
Guard!
怎么样
Hey, how'd it go?
如果你想问宝拉有没有同意我代理她
Well, if you're wondering if I convinced Paula to take me on,
答案是同意了
the answer is yes.
我现在是她的律师了
I am her lawyer now.
我们明天上午要和解谈判
We have a settlement meeting tomorrow,
而且我们不能再谈论这件事了
and this is the last we will speak about it ever again.
-路易...  -不  哈维
- Louis-- - No, Harvey.
宝拉现在是我的委托人
Paula is my client now,
我不想还得一边担心着你因为觉得
and I don't wanna have to worry about you sticking your nose in a case
自己做得比我好要随便插手
that you think you can handle better than me.
-我没觉得...  -要是你能做得比我好
- I don't think-- - Because if you could handle it better than me,
你就自己做了  但你不能
you would, but you can't,
因为你容易陷入其中  你也明白这一点
because you're too involved, and you know it.
你说得对  你会处理好的
You're right. She's in good hands.
-我不插手了  -还不够
- I'll stay out of your way. - Ah, no. Not good enough.
你得向我保证  否则我这就不干了
I want your word, because I will drop it right now.
好  路易  我向你保证
Okay, Louis, you have my word.
哈维  你和路易还好吧
Harvey. Everything okay with you and Louis?
挺好  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
他说在帮你处理一件私事
'Cause he said he was handling a matter for you,
但他不告诉我是什么
but he wouldn't tell me what it was,
而且五分钟之前我看见你俩
and five minutes ago I saw the two of you
正在激烈讨论什么
having an intense discussion.
一切都好
Everything's okay,
那不是激烈讨论
and it wasn't an intense discussion.
只是战略会谈
It was a strategic meeting,
你不用参与进来
so you don't need to get involved.
我也不想参与进来
I wasn't trying to get involved.
我是来告诉你  瑞克・邓恩
I was coming to tell you that Rick Dunn's
已经在你办公室等了十五分钟了
been waiting in your office for 15 minutes.
十五分钟  你怎么不早点告诉我
15 minutes? Why didn't you come and get me right away?
因为我路过的时候才看到他
Because I only just noticed him when I walked by,
而且我已经不是你的秘书了
and I'm not your secretary anymore.
我是事务所的首席运营官
I'm COO of this firm,
所以别批评我加班到这么晚了
so instead of criticizing me for working late,
去看看他要干什么吧
why don't you go see what he wants?
瑞克  要是我知道你要见我
Rick, I could have come to your office
我就去你办公室了
if I'd known you wanted to see me.
要是有人躲着我  我就主动去找他
Well, when someone's avoiding me, I come to them.
没人要躲着你
No one's avoiding anyone.
我想一会给你打电话的
I was gonna give you a call later.
要是你有好消息  早就打电话了
And if you had good news, you'd have done it already.
所以到底发生什么了
So what the hell happened?
你觉得呢  他们什么都不承认
What do you think happened? They denied everything
他们说是自己开发了那项技术
and said they developed that technology on their own.
我不在乎他们说什么
Well, I don't give a shit what they said.
你说过会给我结果
You said you could get me results.
我会给  但我没说一次见面就有结果
And I will, but I didn't say it would take just one meeting.
我来告诉你这次见面之后发生了什么
Well, let me tell you what happened after that one meeting.
他们刚刚宣布  要提前一个月发布
They just announced they're moving up their launch by a month.
听我说  瑞克
Rick, listen to me.
他们不会提前的
They're not moving anything up.
这只是吓唬人  我向你保证
It's a bluff, and I give you my word,
他们不会把你的产品推向市场
they'll never go to market with your product.
你还是听我说吧
Now you listen to me.
你说一次见面拿不到结果
You said you wouldn't have anything after one meeting.
那你最好能在两次见面之后拿到结果
Well, you sure as hell better have it after two.
否则  我会让所有人知道
Because if you don't, I'm gonna tell everyone in the city
哈维・斯佩克特唯一擅长的
that the only thing Harvey Specter is good at
就是做不能兑现的承诺
is making promises he can't keep.
见鬼
Shit.
根本没有任何证明囚犯
There's no paper trail
因为挑事掐架受奖赏的书面记录
proving any inmates were rewarded for picking fights.
好吧  柯林斯不肯说
Okay. Just because Collins didn't talk
不表示其他三个人不会说
doesn't mean the other three won't.
你知道他们也不会说的
Yes, it does, and you know it.
而且他们都没法缓刑
And none of them are close to parole,
所以我们也没法用缓刑来诱惑他们
which means we don't even have that to offer.
好吧  我们再回头看看狱警这边
Okay, then let's go back through the guards again.
我跟你说过行不通
I told you, that's a dead end.
布伦斯维克的监狱由系统随机分配牢房变动
Brunswick has a system of randomly assigning changes.
那就跳出布伦斯维克的范围
Then let's start looking outside of Brunswick.
见鬼
Holy shit.
你说得对
You're right.
他们还有八座监狱
They own eight other prisons,
如果他们在这一座监狱干这种事
and if they're doing this in one--
其他七座监狱肯定也是一样
Then they're doing it at the other seven.
或许有一座监狱不太会掩盖踪迹
And maybe one of them isn't as good at covering their tracks.
说对了  那赶紧吧
Bingo. All right, let's do it.
因为我现在应该和瑞秋一起吃晚饭
'Cause I'm supposed to be at dinner right now with Rachel,
而不是和你翻文件
not going through files with you.
你要找哪份
Take your pick.
沃巴什  达尔顿
Wabash, Dalton,
兰伯特  布莱克威尔...
Lambert and Blackwell--
等等  你说兰伯特
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Lambert?
兰伯特惩教所属于改造公司吗
Lambert Correctional Institute is owned by Reform Corp?
怎么了  那里有你认识的人吗
Yeah, why? You know someone there?
不
No.
我知道有人以前在那里呆过
No, I know somebody who used to be there.
他是那种会知道点什么东西的人吗
He the kinda guy who'd know something?
他是那种什么都知道的人
He's the kinda guy that would know everything.
瑞秋  你见迈克了吗  他不在办公室
Rachel, have you seen Mike? He's not in his office.
他早些时候去诊所了
He left earlier this morning for the clinic,
肯定是还在那儿
so he must still be there.
又去了  我让他快点办完那个案子的
Again? I told him to wrap that case up.
哈维  他既履行你的约定又要为
Harvey, he's working hard to live up to your deal
其他客户工作  他很辛苦的
and still come through for his other clients.
我现在需要他
Well, right now I need him,
每次去去他办公室总是看不到他
and I'm getting a little tired of looking into his office
我已经有点烦了
and finding it empty.
或许我可以帮你做点什么
Maybe there's something I can do to help you.
不用
No, it's fine.
告诉他我在找他就好
Just let him know I'm looking for him.
不过既然你提到了  确实有件事
Actually, now that you mention it, there is one thing.
听说你回去找霍莉・科伦维尔了
I heard you went back to Holly Cromwell.
是的  迈克和我去的  有问题吗
Yes, Mike and I did. Is there a problem?
没有
No, there's no problem.
我只想知道她起到作用了吗
I just want to know if she came through.
关于费用的问题  她为难了我们一下
Well, she stuck it to us on the fee a little,
但除此之外  是的  很大作用
but other than that, yeah, she came through.
值得吗
Was it worth it?
这么说吧  他们写的这篇迈克的文章
Let me put it this way, the article they wrote about Mike,
如果没有她  根本就不会成
it never would have existed without her.
竟然是迈克・罗斯
If it isn't Mike Ross.
你应该不是来卖女童军饼干的吧
I take it you're not here selling Girl Scout cookies,
但如果你真的是  给我来两盒去你妈的味
but if you are, I'll take two boxes of go fu-- yourself.
先坐下  加洛
Just sit down, Gallo.
我比你更不想来
I don't want to be here any more than you do,
但我需要你的帮助
but I need your help.
上次我帮了你  结果判了五年
Last time I helped you, I got five years for my trouble.
这个问题我们可能有点办法
Well, maybe we can do something about that.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
这是起诉你之前那间监狱的
That is a lawsuit against your former prison,
起诉他们恶意挑拨犯人斗殴
for starting fights with inmates
以此来延长他们的刑期
so that they could extend their sentences,
我想让你做专家证人
and I want you to be an expert witness.
你是在玩我
You gotta be shitting me.
-弗兰克  -省省吧
- Frank-- - Save your breath.
我不可能做这个的
There's not a chance in hell I'm doing this.
如果我说  我能让你力有所值呢
What if I told you I could make it worth your while?
无所谓
It doesn't matter
因为我根本不懂你在说什么
because I don't know what the hell you're talking about anyway.
胡说  你指望我相信
Bullshit. You expect me to believe
这里的所有狱警都是你的人
that you own all the guards in here,
但上一间监狱有阴谋你就毫不知情
but you didn't know about a conspiracy at your last prison?
你好像知道得不少
Sounds like you know a whole hell of a lot.
你想让我干嘛
What do you need me for?
我需要有人告诉我全部的事情
I need somebody to tell me everything,
作为交换  我愿意
and in exchange I am willing to--
我来告诉你你愿意做什么
I'll tell you what you're willing to do.
之前你答应过的
What you promised to do in the first place.
你要把我捞出去
You're gonna get me out of here.
你知道我不行的
You know I can't do that.
放屁  那个叫卡荷尔欠你份大人情
Bullshit. That Cahill guy owes you big time.
你就大大方方走进去
March those pretty little feet in there
把该说的都说了
and say what has to be said,
不然的话  你别想知道一点消息
or you won't know anything about anything.
你在忙这个事的时候
While you're at it,
下次进来的时候记得给我带个饼干
next time you're here bring me a goddamn cookie.
希望你有时间看看我的和解提议
Hope you had time to look over the settlement offer I sent.
坦白说  利特先生  价格太低了
To be frank, Mr. Litt, this number's so low,
我们连还价都懒得
we won't even be countering.
我们不会和自己讨价还价的
We're not negotiating against ourselves.
那你是想我回去跟自己谈判吗
Oh, no, you want me to negotiate against myself.
那我也告诉你  这个数字本来应该是0的
Let me tell you something, that number should be zero.
但是阿加德医生愿意花一点钱
But Dr. Agard is willing to pay something
让这件事过去
in order to put this matter behind her.
但她却不愿意来见我  不愿意承认她错了
But she's not willing to face me and own up to what she did.
她所做的  曼宁医生  是在照顾你的病人
All she did, Dr. Manning, was care for your patients.
说明她违反了他们的合伙人协议
Which means she violated their partnership agreement.
根据希波克拉底誓言
And according to the Hippocratic Oath,
对病人的照顾可以取代任何法律协议
patient care supersedes any legal agreement.
她根本不在乎那些病人
She didn't care about those patients.
她只是想偷我的生意罢了
She just wanted to steal my business.
真的吗  那他们为什么会联系她
Really? Then why did they contact her?
你又没有证据
You have no proof of that.
我有  我有电话记录
Yes, I do. I have phone records.
我的客户有道德义务
My client had an ethical obligation
去照顾那些病人
to care for those patients.
那医生不该睡病人的
And what about her ethical obligation
-道德义务呢  -你说什么
- not to sleep with a patient? - What'd you just say?
我知道她和哈维・斯佩克特有一腿
I know that she's been running around with Harvey Specter,
所以他的合伙人来帮她辩护  也不稀奇
and it's no surprise that it's his partner defending her.
阿加德医生的私人生活与本案无关
Dr. Agard's personal life has no bearing on this case.
可有关系了
Oh it'll have plenty of bearing
尤其是道德委员会发现
when the ethics board learn
她在强制等待期结束前
that she started dating one of her patients
就已经开始和她的一位病人约会了
before the mandatory waiting period elapsed.
这是赤裸裸的谎言
That's a bald-faced lie,
你是为了勒索我的客户在歪曲事实
and now you're twisting facts in order to blackmail my client.
勒索可是非常严重的指控了
Blackmail is a serious accusation.
我的客户从来没为他的沉默要过任何回报
My client never asked for anything in exchange for his silence.
他刚才那话就是暗示
Well, he sure as shit implied it.
会议结束  利特先生
This meeting's over, Mr. Litt.
你为什么不花一晚冷静一下
Why don't you take the evening to cool down?
好好想想报价
Think of a real number.
伟大的哈维・斯佩克特
The great Harvey Specter
专门从十四街远道而来见我
came all the way below 14th Street to see me.
-荣幸之至  -我能说什么呢
- I'm honored. - What can I say?
有好消息的时候  我喜欢当面说
When I have good news, I like to deliver it face-to-face.
所以是你已经准备好雇我了
Does that mean you're ready to hire me?
还没有  但是如果你帮我搞定一件事
Not yet, but if you take care of something for me,
我应该就没问题了
I just might be.
洛克伍德要发行一款太阳能电池板
Lockwood's launching a solar panel?
他们什么时候涉足可再生能源了
Since when are they in the renewable energy business?
从他们偷了加尔万达因的技术开始
Since they stole the technology from Galvadyne.
不可能  他们没偷
No way. They didn't steal it.
你怎么知道
How can you know that?
因为只有六个人有这个能力
Because there's only six people capable of that kind of work,
如果他们中有人做了  我会知道的
and if one of them did it, I'd know.
可他们确实拿到了
Well, they got it somehow,
我要知道他们是怎么拿到的
and I need to know how they did it.
好像也不是很难的事嘛
That's not a hell of a lot to go on.
如果我有更多证据  我也不会需要你了
If I had more to go on, I wouldn't need you.
换句话说  你想让我完成不可能的任务
In other words, you want me to do the impossible to audition
来面试一份你昨天说的结果根本不存在的工作
for a job you told me yesterday didn't even exist?
那就把它想成是魔术
Then consider it a magic trick.
你让这个信息弄出来了
You make this information appear,
突然之间  你的工作也出现了
all of a sudden, so does that job.
那就快选一间办公室
Then start picking out an office,
因为下次你再接到我的电话
because the next time you hear from me,
我就要搬进来了
I'm moving in.
你一早上的都去哪儿了
Where the hell have you been all morning?
我去证监会见肖恩・卡荷尔了
I went to see Sean Cahill at the S.E.C.
我不想告诉你的  迈克
I hate to break it to you, Mike,
但证监会对私人监狱没有管辖权
but the S.E.C. doesn't have jurisdiction over private prisons.
我知道  我是在和弗兰克・加洛谈条件
I know that. I was trying to cut Frank Gallo a deal.
他说他会作证了吗
He said he'll testify?
除非拿到假释  但是卡荷尔不给
Not unless he gets parole, and Cahill said no.
说明我们得过一遍加洛的档案
Which means we need to go through Gallo's files,
看能不能找到别的办法放他出来
see if we can find another way to get him released.
迈克  迈克  等一下
Mike, Mike, hold up a second.
加洛的档案说他在丹伯里监狱
Gallo's files said he got an extra five years
因使用致命武器袭击他人而加刑五年
for assault with a deadly weapon while he was at Danbury.
所以呢
So?
所以差不多是在你出来的时候
So that's pretty damn close to when you got outta there.
迈克
Mike.
这是那个之前要杀了你的人吗
Is this the guy who tried to kill you?
-奥利佛  -天呐  迈克
- Oliver-- - Jesus, Mike!
我们不能让这样的人出来
We can't put a guy like that out on the street.
我不是现在就要把他捞出来
I'm not trying to get him out now.
我是让他早两年出来
All right, I'm gonna get him out two years early,
所以从现在算还有五年
which is still five years from now.
而且如果我不这么做
And in the meantime if I don't do that,
又有多少人会像克里斯・雷耶斯一样
how many guys are gonna end up just like Chris Reyes?
现在我担心你会像克里斯・雷耶斯一样
Right now I'm worried about you ending up like Chris Reyes.
如果加洛要对付我
If Gallo is gonna come after me,
不管是五年还是七年  都无所谓了
it doesn't matter if it's in five years or seven.
我的参与很快就会变得太过危险
We only have so long before me working on this becomes too risky,
所以这是唯一的办法
which means this is the only way.
好的
Okay.
但是我见过你做到了别的律师做不到的事情
But I've seen you do things no other lawyer could.
你有足够的脑子来说服加洛
You're sure as shit smart enough to convince this guy
接受除假释外的其他条件
to take something besides parole.
你不懂弗兰克・加洛
You don't know Frank Gallo.
但我懂你教我的话
What I know is what you taught me.
每个人都有自己想要的东西
Everybody has something they want.
意味着你只用找到
Which means all you have to do is find out
加洛想要的其他东西  然后满足他
whatever else Gallo wants and give it to him.
路易  怎么样了
Louis, hello. How did it go?
听我说  如果我要做你的律师
Listen to me, if I'm gonna be your attorney,
你就得跟我说实话
I need you to tell me the goddamn truth.
我不喜欢你的语气  我告诉了你实话
I'm not sure I like your tone. I told you the truth.
是吗  因为我得知道
Did you? Because I need to know
在哈维还是你病人的时候
if you started seeing Harvey
你是否就开始跟他约会
while he was still your patient.
什么  没有  谁告诉你的
What? No. Who told you that?
你的前任  他威胁要把这件事告诉委员会
Your ex, and he's threatening to go to the board with it.
如果有任何证据证明...
If there is one shred of proof--
不会有什么证据  因为事情没发生过
There isn't any proof, because it didn't happen.
如果你不愿相信
And if you don't care to believe that,
那你可以直接转身走人
then you can turn around and walk right out.
因为我不屑让一个质疑我人品的人
Because I don't care to be represented by a man
做我的代理律师
who questions my integrity.
好吧  对不起
Okay, I am sorry.
我只是不喜欢措手不及
I just don't like being blindsided.
那我很高兴你受的惊吓已经过去了
Well, I'm glad your shock is behind you,
但我受的还没有
but mine isn't.
你说他会告诉委员会是什么意思
What do you mean he's going to the board?
他以此作为威胁
I mean he is blackmailing you
想要敲诈你
with the threat of going to the board.
什么
What?
这会毁了我的事业
That would ruin my career.
我知道  所以你现在得告诉我
I know, which is why you need to tell me
你和雅各布之间到底发生了什么
what really happened between you and Jacob now.
路易  说这个我会感觉不舒服
Louis, I don't feel comfortable doing that.
抱歉  宝拉  但你必须这样做
I'm sorry, Paula, but you're gonna have to,
因为反驳他的唯一辩词
because the only defense against what he is trying to do
就是真相
is the truth.
当我告诉你他伤了我的心
When I told you he broke my heart,
我说的就是真相
I was telling the truth.
但我没告诉你的是在那之后
But what I didn't tell you was that after that
他改变了心意
he changed his mind.
唐娜  我需要你为一名新员工
Donna, I need you to draw up some paperwork
起草入职文件
for a new employee.
我明天一大早就办
I'll get to it first thing in the morning.
等等
Wait a second,
我们为什么要请霍莉・科伦维尔做顾问
why are we bringing on Holly Cromwell as a consultant?
因为她很厉害  而且我不想每次要她帮忙
Because she kicks ass, and I don't want to have to track her down
都得费劲去找她
every time I need her help with something.
哈维  我认为这是个错误的决定
Harvey, I think this is a mistake.
这我说了算
Well, it's my call.
不  事实上你不能说了算
No, actually it isn't.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我说过  我不再是你的秘书了
I told you, I'm not your secretary anymore.
我现在是首席运营官  你提拔我是有原因的
I'm COO, and you made me that for a reason.
我很会看人  然后我告诉你
I know people, and I'm telling you it's reckless
雇用一个有背叛雇主经历的人
to hire someone who betrayed her employer
相当轻率
the first chance she got.
唐娜  我向她保证过
Donna, I gave her my word
如果她帮忙我就雇用她
I'd do this if she came through,
她会帮忙的
she's gonna come through,
而且我已经对她失信过一次了
and I already broke my word to her once.
或许你不该向一个不是律师的人
Well, then maybe you shouldn't promise a job
承诺一份律所工作
at a law firm to someone who isn't a lawyer.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
你就不是个律师  我也提拔你了
You're not a lawyer, I just promoted you,
依我说  结果还相当不错
and that worked out pretty damn well if you ask me.
你是在我证明了对律所的忠诚后
And you only did that after I proved
才这么做的
my loyalty to this firm.
那现在她也会证明她的忠诚
And she's gonna start proving her loyalty now.
需要我提醒你...
Need I remind you that--
提醒我你是老大吗  不  你不用
That you're in charge? No, you don't.
而且如果你想告诉我
And if you try to give me your,
"这事不需要投票表决"这种鬼话
"This isn't something we vote on" Bullshit,
我会找到路易  马上带他过来
I will find out where Louis is, and I will bring him
再带上一份公司章程
down here right now with a copy of the bylaws,
因为我敢肯定这就是我们需要投票表决的事
because I am betting it is something we vote on.
好吧  唐娜  你赢了
Okay, Donna, you win.
你不想雇她  那就不雇
You don't wanna hire her, we won't.
但这件事做决定的是你
But you wanna be the one to make that call,
那也由你来当面拒绝她
you're gonna be the one to tell her to her face.
饿了吗  厨房里还剩有一些泰国菜
You hungry? There's some leftover Thai in the kitchen.
太好了  我饿死了  一整天没吃饭了
Great, I'm starving. Haven't eaten all day.
迈克  我知道我说过
Mike, about that, I know I said that maybe
也许你该请求哈维给你点休息时间
you should ask Harvey for a little time off
来帮助诊所
to help with the clinic,
但我在想是否
but I'm wondering if maybe
你也该从诊所
you should take a little time off
争取点休息时间来帮助哈维
from the clinic to help Harvey.
-瑞秋  -他今天在找你
- Rachel-- - He was looking for you today,
而且显然不是第一次了
and it was clear it wasn't the first time.
你自己说过  当初他能答应
And you said yourself, he was nice enough
这笔交易已经很宽容了
to make this deal in the first place,
所以也许是时候记住他的好了
so maybe it's time to remember that.
我没忘记过
I do remember that.
我们现在不会一起完成每一个案子
It's not like we work on every case together.
他知道的
He knows that.
我也知道
And I know that, too.
但他让你回律所是有原因的
But he brought you back for a reason,
所以当他真的需要你的时候
and that's so that when he does need you,
你得在
you'll be there.
你说得对
You're right.
我只是...在处理布鲁克林房屋的案子
I'm just--I'm working on this Brooklyn Housing thing,
有截止期限
and there's a deadline.
但这事一结束
But as soon as it is over,
我就暂时不去诊所了
I will take a break from the clinic.
我保证
Promise.
好
Okay.
你买了我爱吃的春卷吗
Now, did you get the spring rolls that I like?
有
Yes.
没有  可能没了吧
No. Maybe?
你吃光了  对吗
You ate them all, didn't you?
它们都在呼唤我的名字
Well, they were calling out my name.
-每次都这样  -你知道的
- Every time! - You know that.
都是调味汁的错
It's the sauce!
路易  我们以前从未讨论过案子的细节
Louis, we've never discussed the specifics of a case before.
为什么你突然觉得这个案子如此重要
Why do you think this one is so important all of a sudden?
我不知道
I don't know.
她一直在对我说关于这个人
She kept telling me all these horrible things
所有可怕的事  但是...
about this guy, but...
但是什么  路易
But what, Louis?
她还告诉我
She also told me that
他做这一切只想让她回到自己身边
all he wanted to do was get her back.
她为他感到很遗憾
She felt sorry for him.
我想我也为他感到遗憾
I guess I felt sorry for him, too.
为他还是为你自己遗憾
Sorry for him or for yourself?
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
路易  我讨厌拿你做类比
Louis, I hate to draw comparisons for you,
但有没有可能你把自己
but is there a chance you're putting yourself
代入了这个男人的处境  因为他的遭遇
in this man's shoes because it's so similar
很像你和塔拉的经历
to what happened between you and Tara?
-我没有背叛她  -但你表现很差
- I didn't cheat on her. - But you behaved poorly.
因此结束了恋情  而你想要她回来
It ended the relationship, and you wanted her back.
我说过我不想再
And I told you that I do not want
谈论和塔拉做了结的事
to talk about getting closure with Tara anymore.
我知道  路易  但不断向你提起这事
I know that, Louis, but it is my duty
是我的责任
to keep bringing it up to you.
否则我们为什么还要见面
Otherwise, why are we seeing each other?
好吧  那么  医生
Okay, then, Doc,
说实话  我不认为是这个原因
honestly, I don't think that's it.
那你去做你知道你该做的事
Then you shouldn't have any trouble
应该也没什么困难
doing what you know you have to do.
-霍莉  对吧  -是的
- Holly, right? - Yes.
唐娜・鲍尔森  谢谢你这么早见我
I'm Donna Paulsen. Thanks for meeting me so early.
没事  我们可以私下交流交易要点
No problem. We can go over the deal points informally,
但我需要在我签名前  先让我的
but I will need my lawyer to take a look at the contract
律师过目
before I sign.
事实上  我还有几个问题
Actually, I have a few questions for you first.
什么问题
What kind of questions?
判断你是否
The kind that determine
适合皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特的问题
if you're Pearson Specter Litt material.
你叫我来不是为了讨论我的合同吧
I'm not here for my contract, am I?
我来是因为你对我有意见
I'm here because you have a problem with me.
我是对你有意见
I do have a problem with you.
我明白了  我早该知道的
I see what this is. I should have known.
我有沃顿商学院的工商管理硕士学位  荣誉毕业
I have an MBA from Wharton, I graduated with honors,
你就觉得我只是个高价...
and you think all I am is a high-priced--
不  我才不在乎你对男人和性的态度
No, I don't give a shit what you think about sex and men.
我的问题是你做的生意有背叛惯性
My problem is that you're in the betrayal business.
你背叛你看上的男人
You betray the men that you prey on,
而我们和你的唯一一次接触中
and then the only time we had an interaction with you,
你也背叛了你的雇主
you turned on your employer.
那你为什么不向你的雇主提这个问题
Well, why don't you bring that up with your employer?
因为就是他让我处于了那个处境
Because he's the one who got me in that position.
那是我第一次  也是最后一次这么做
It was the first and last time I ever did anything like that,
而且为此我还失去了工作
and I lost my livelihood because of it.
这我倒不知道
I didn't know that.
谨慎和正直是我工作的基础
Discretion and integrity were the foundations of my business.
你的老板摧毁了它们  所以我不喜欢
Your boss knocked them down, and I don't appreciate you
你来质疑我是否一开始就具有这些品质
questioning whether or not they were there in the first place.
这是什么
What's this?
这是我本来打算交给我新雇主的东西
That is what I thought I'd be delivering to my new employer.
这正是哈维需要的东西
This is exactly what Harvey needed.
你怎么弄到的
How the hell did you get this?
我做的  是艺术
What I do is an art.
我能发现人们的需要  恐惧
I find out what people want, what they're afraid of,
他们的命门  然后加以利用
what makes them tick, and I use it.
他们不会知道整体局面
And they never know the big picture,
所以他们会给我我需要的  还毫不知情
so when they give me what I need, they think it's nothing.
等你把这些碎片拼起来
And then when you put all the pieces together,
就成了你的委托人需要的东西
it adds up to exactly what your clients are looking for.
那是我保证哈维弄到的东西
That's everything I promised I'd get Harvey,
而且只用了不到一天
and it took me less than a day.
我遵守了承诺
I kept my word.
我的饼干呢
Where's my cookie?
给你带了比饼干更好的东西
Brought you something better than a cookie.
你也曾是改造公司的犯人
You were a prisoner under Reform Corp, too,
也就是说现在你也是集体诉讼的一员了
which means you are now a member of the class.
赢了这场官司  等你出狱时就不是
We win this, you're not Brooks Hatlen bagging groceries
就不再是为食物发愁布鲁克斯・哈特兰
at the Food-Way when you get out.
而是躺在墨西哥沙滩上的安迪・杜佛兰
You're gonna be Andy Dufresne sitting on a beach in Mexico
两人都是电影《肖申克的救赎》里的人物
后者是男主人公
带着一个满满的钱包
with a bank account full of cash.
我在这里本来过的就不错
I already make a nice living in here.
确实  但我觉得这笔钱的一部分
You do, but I was thinking maybe some of that money
-可以给你女儿  -你说什么
- might go to your daughter. - What'd you just say to me?
我做了调查  弗兰克  我知道你和她不来往了
I did some digging, Frank. I know you don't talk to her.
她的处境不好  这么多钱
And she is not doing great, and this much money
可以彻底改变她的生活
could really change her life.
如果你这是耍我...
If you're playing with me on this thing--
我没有耍你  弗兰克
I'm not playing you, Frank.
我没有想以此威胁你
And I'm not trying to bully you with this.
我是想帮你
I'm trying to help you.
我们是有协议
We had an arrangement.
直接由监狱代理的吗
Brokered directly by the prison?
开始不是  但我看出了规律
Not at first, but I saw the pattern.
打伤人就有奖
Break some skulls, get a reward.
所以我找到了源头  谈正式协议
So I went to the source to get things codified.
-成功了吗  -是的
- And did you? - Yeah.
弄清了事情的内幕
Found out what was what.
开始挺好  后来我意识到
It was good at first, then I realized
那就像为黑帮做事
it was like working for the mob.
拿到时是份好工作  但不能辞职
Great work while you can get it, but you can never quit.
所以我想抽身
So I tried to put an end to the whole thing.
那晚狱警关了监控
That night the guards killed the cameras,
五个我所谓的朋友揍了我一顿
and five of my so-called friends did a number on me.
等等  你是在说让你来了
Wait a second. Are you saying this the deal
丹伯里的交易吗
that got you to Danbury?
你已经告发过这个人了吗
You already informed on this guy?
没有  你吃白痴吗
No, what are you, nuts?
没人在乎犯人的待遇
No one cares how prisoners are treated.
我告发的是真正犯了罪的一个罪犯
I informed on real guys about real crimes.
所以才出来了
That's how I got out.
你愿意把这些话作为呈堂证供吗
Are you willing to go on the record with this?
告诉我你的消息来源
Tell me your source?
没那么简单  小迈克
It's not gonna be that easy, Mikey.
我需要你预付我和解费
I'm gonna need an advance on that settlement.
请坐
Please, sit down.
很高兴你带了有诚意的数字  利特先生
Glad to see you've come back with a real number, Mr. Litt.
我唯一带来的
The only number I'm back with
就是教训你的委托人的打算
is the one that I'm gonna do on your client.
搞什么  你说他打算开支票了的
What the hell? You said he was ready to cut a check.
她应该告诉你的是  雅各布
Oh, well, what she should have told you, Jacob,
你勒索别人
is when you threaten someone with blackmail,
最好是准备好迎战的
you better goddamn be ready to defend yourself.
你最好注意对我委托人的用词
And you better watch how you talk to my client.
你的委托人就是个撒谎  出轨的混蛋
You client is a lying, cheating piece of shit,
他起诉前任的唯一动机就是报复
whose only motive for suing his ex is to get revenge.
-她破坏了我们的约定  -不  是你破坏在先
- She broke our agreement. - No, you broke your agreement
你出轨两个月
when you had an affair for two months
还打算离开她就是破坏约定
and you thought you were gonna leave her.
那件事和本案无关
That has nothing to do with this suit.
那件事和本案关系很大
It's got everything to do with this suit.
你看  是你搞砸了  你改了主意
You see, you messed up. You changed your mind
但当她决定断绝关系
and you wouldn't take no for an answer
你又不愿意  所以这一年来
when she ended it, and that's why you've been
你才一直跟踪她
stalking her for the last year.
我没有跟踪她
I haven't been stalking her.
瞧瞧  宣誓书上下册
Bang. Signed affidavits one and two.
和你无中生有的指控不一样
Unlike your bullshit accusations,
我有实在的证据  从你雇来
I have actual proof from the agency
跟踪她的机构  到报刊亭那个作证
that you hired to follow her, to the guy at the news stand
你每天有一半时间站在那里盯着她的公寓
who says you stand there half the day watching her building.
雅各布  这是真的吗
Jacob, is this true?
是真的  他自己心里清楚
It is true. He knows it's true.
这可是D级重罪  医生
And that is a Class D felony, Doctor.
我应该报警抓你
I should have you arrested,
或者  我应该去医师协会
or maybe I'll just go to the board,
吊销你的执照
have your license removed.
我们本来应该拥有幸福的生活
We were going to have a life together.
我把一切都计划好了
I planned everything out.
我们要在哪里生活  生几个孩子
Where we were going to live, how many kids we'd have,
结婚纪念日去哪里过
where we'd go on our anniversary.
我就犯了一个错误
And then I make a mistake,
紧接着
and the next thing I know,
这整个生活都没了
my whole life was gone.
我们撤诉
We'll be dropping the suit.
你找奥利佛吗
You looking for Oliver?
纳森  你好
Nathan, hey.
是啊  我有些事
Uh, yeah, just had some things
要跟他说
that I wanted to run by him.
布鲁克林租房案还是监狱诉讼案
On the Brooklyn Housing case or on your prison lawsuit?
纳森  我没办法...
Look, Nathan, I had to
迈克  镇定
Mike, come on, relax.
我没生气
I'm not angry.
虽然我现在是很想把你的表情拍下来
Though I do wish I had a picture of your face right now.
-你怎么看出来的  -逗我吗
- What tipped you off? - Come on, are you kidding me?
你签下那个协议的时候
I mean, the second you signed that agreement,
我就知道你会后悔
I knew you'd go back on it.
那你为什么不揭穿我
So then why didn't you say anything?
因为这次你要坑的人不是我
Because this time you're screwing over
是哈维・斯佩克特
Harvey Specter and not me.
要么你打赢案子
Look, you're either gonna win this thing
我们得利
and we're gonna get all the credit,
要么你事情败露被抓
or you're gonna get caught with your hand
那我们撤诉
in the cookie jar, and we'll drop the case.
对我没什么损失
I have no downside.
奥利佛知道吗
Does Oliver know?
知道  我假装生气
Yeah, yeah, I pretended to be pissed at him
赶他回家了
and sent him home.
迈克  回家好好休息
Look, Mike, why don't you take the night
想想你为我赢得了多少尊重
and think about how much respect you just gained for me,
明早再来大杀四方
then come back and kill it in the morning.
谢谢你  纳森
Thanks, Nathan.
不客气  迈克
You're welcome, Mike.
唐娜  今晚回家前
Donna, before you go home tonight,
我需要你给我替霍莉开张支票
I need you to cut me a check for Holly.
什么意思  给她的钱都在工资里了
What do you mean? I'm gonna put her on the payroll.
她不来这里工作了
She doesn't want to work here anymore.
她说宁愿做一次性工作
Said she'd rather do one-off jobs if at all.
这是金额
Here's the amount.
我不明白  我不反对她来了
I don't understand. I was good with having her.
不管你说了什么  让她不愿意来了
Well, whatever you said made her not good with having us.
哈维  我们是个紧密的团队
Harvey, we're a tight-knit group.
我们不背叛对方
We don't betray each other
也没有事隐瞒对方
and we don't keep secrets from each other.
我必须知道她的立场
I had to find out where she stood.
如果代价是她拒绝来这里
And if the cost of that was her not coming here,
那我也不后悔
then I don't regret it.
我理解  唐娜
I understand, Donna.
我不是在责怪你
I'm not coming down on you.
我只是需要支票
I just need the check.
哈维  是不是这个女人
Harvey, is there something
还有什么事是你没告诉我的
that you're not telling me about this woman?
因为最近觉得你变了个人
'Cause it seems like you've been different lately,
我不知道
and...I don't know.
和她没关系
It's nothing about this woman.
我只是以为她会是个很好的员工
I just thought she'd be a good addition.
这种事很正常
These things happen.
有意思
It's funny.
我很爱我的新工作  但我很怀念这样
I love my new position, but I miss this.
我也怀念
I miss it, too.
要我给你倒点喝的吗
You want me to pour us a couple drinks?
或许明天吧
Maybe tomorrow night.
现在我还有事要办
I have something I have to deal with right now.
好
Okay.
我给你开支票
I'll cut you that check.
你是对的  医生
You were right, Doc.
我一直没有处理塔拉的事
I hadn't really dealt with Tara.
但有一件事很明确
But one thing is clear.
这个状况是我造成的
The situation was my doing.
也就是说
Which means...
我应该开始解决自己的问题了
I need to keep working on myself,
因为
because...
我不想再搞砸我的下一段认真恋情了
I don't wanna mess things up with the next Tara.
路易  一般我是
Louis, typically I refrain
避免对我的患者说这种话的  但是
from saying things like this to my patients, but...
我为你骄傲
I am proud of you.
晚安  医生
Good night, Doc.
晚安  路易
Good night, Louis.
有时间再见一个患者吗
Time for one more appointment?
你好  你怎么来了
Hello. What are you doing here?
我想带你出去庆祝
I wanted to take you out and celebrate.
路易都告诉我了
Louis told me what happened.
我刚跟他通完电话
I just got off the phone with him.
他干得很好
He did an amazing job.
而你推荐了他也算干得不错
And you did an amazing job recommending him.
为什么没告诉我雅各布的事
Why didn't you tell me about Jacob?
我让路易别告诉你的
I asked Louis not to tell you that.
-路易没有  -那你是怎么...
- Louis didn't tell me. - Well, then how do you--
我就是知道  但我只是希望
Because I do, and all I could think of
你能给我足够的信任  相信我
was I wish you trusted me enough to know
不会为他对你做的事去找他麻烦
that I wouldn't go nuts on this guy for what he did to you.
你以为我不告诉你是这个原因吗
Is that why you think I didn't tell you?
你确实了解我和不忠的人的渊源
Well, you know my history with infidelity.
还有什么原因
What else could it be?
哈维  他背叛了我
Harvey, the man cheated on me.
我信任了他  他却背叛了我
I trusted him, and he cheated on me,
我是担心你因为这件事会对我产生的看法
and I was afraid of how you'd see me.
他背叛你我为什么会对你产生不同看法
Why would him cheating on you make me see you differently?
因为有些人认为
Because some people think that a woman
会被人背叛的女人
who can be cheated on can't be...
不可爱
loveable.
你这么了解我  怎么还会这么想
How can you know me and think that?
但事不关你  而是我
Well, it's not about you. It's about me.
如果这个人这么对你
And if this guy did this to you,
说明他是个白痴  是他
then he's an idiot, and all he did
失去了一个很宝贵的东西
is lose out on something great.
居然觉得自己不可爱
Not loveable?
心理医生也不是什么都知道的
Psychiatrists don't know everything, you know.
我发现了
I'm starting to realize that.
你真是夜以继日啊
You really are burning the candle at both ends.
给我的吗
Hey. Is this for me?
你都忙得没法回家吃晚饭了
Since you were too busy to come to dinner,
我就想  只能让晚饭去找你了
I thought, why can't dinner come to you?
我没懂  什么叫晚饭来找我
I don't understand. What do you mean, come to me?
我带它去诊所找你了  迈克  你不在
I brought it to the clinic, Mike, but you weren't there.
肯定是我还没回去呢
I just--I must have not been back yet.
从哪里
Back from where?
是布鲁克林的养老院
Was it the nursing home in Brooklyn
还是住房部
or was it the Department of Buildings?
因为奥利佛  他好像不确定是哪个
Because Oliver, he couldn't seem to decide which.
-瑞秋  我...  -迈克  如果你
- Rachel, I didn't-- - Mike, if you can't tell me
不告诉我怎么回事  只会让我去想
what's going on, I'm gonna start to wonder
你还有什么别的事瞒着我
what else you've been keeping from me.
我确实是在跟奥利佛办案
I wasn't lying about working a case with Oliver.
我只是没告诉你是哪件
I just didn't tell you which one.
监狱案
The prison one.
-是的  -你签了协议
- Yeah. - You signed an agreement.
这是要被辞退的
This is a fireable offense.
哈维不会就为这解雇...
Harvey isn't gonna fire me for--
-但也许他应该  -你怎么这么说
- Okay, but maybe he should. - How can you say that?
因为你在利用他对你的信任
Because you're taking advantage of his trust,
别说还有我的
not to mention mine.
瑞秋  这些犯人被利用来榨取钱财
Rachel, these prisoners are being exploited for money.
你在做对的事
And you trying to do the right thing
不代表你就可以打破承诺
doesn't change the fact that you gave your word.
-瑞秋  -听着
- Rachel-- - Look...
我们走过这么多风风雨雨
We've been through enough for you to know
出了这件事也不代表我明天就不爱你了
that I'm still gonna love you in the morning,
但你应该扪心自问
but you have to ask yourself:
你的承诺有没有价值
What is your word worth?
因为就目前的事情来看
'Cause with the way things are going,
它已经快要一文不值了
it's not gonna be worth very much.